## **Summary**

Product designer passionate about people and technology. Understanding people behaviour and their habits, I draw experiences from government, urban planning, education and the creative industry. Lean and agile, my purpose is to bridge the gap between users and businesses.

### **Technical**

### JAVASCRIPT

Knockout.js, JQuery, D3.js

#### WIREFRAMING/UI

Axure Adobe Suite

#### **CMS DEVELOPMENT**

Pylons/Pyramid (WSGI framework) CKAN

### SDLC ENVIRONMENTS

Git, JIRA, Visual Studio AWS - Workspaces, EC2, RDS

### **TEMPLATING**

Bootstrap Mustache, Jinja

### ANALYTICS/DB

R, VBA, Numpy, Scipy SQL, Postgresql, Postgis

# Honorable mentions

2015 Geonext Hackathon, 1st place: Open Source API; 2nd runner-up: Government Data

2015 3D Visualization World Magazine, GIS For Understanding and Visualization of Urban Economics

2014 Journal of Location Based Services, Indoor navigation for people who are Blind or Vision Impaired:

Where are we and where are we going?

## **Experience**

# UX/FRONT END DEVELOPER (contract)

04/2016 - 09/2016

### Informed Solutions Australia

Developed a platform that makes sharing and searching large volume of data easy for the government.

Subscribing to MVC and MVVM frameworks, I played a big part in developing the application's business logic and client-side code. Evangelising users' needs, I developed several key features such as Map Search and Data Preview to make viewing large volume of data more intuitive. Key metrics such task time and completion rates were significantly improved by these enhancements.

# CONSULTANT (Digital products)

01/2013 - 04/2016

### SGS Economics and Planning

I helped the consulting business establish a first-of-its-kind "Digital Solutions".

Prior its inception, consultants were delivering complex, data-rich reports in static PDFs. Seeing the limitations it brought to communication, I developed a bespoke service to improve readers' engagement.

I tested my hypothesis and built prototypes to show proof of concept. Gauging clients' acceptance, I looked at metrics such as page views, browsing time. Managing change and building trust, I was inclusive and maintained close contact with people at stake. I asked for feedback and tailored the product to suit their needs. Hands on from design, development, deployment, to maintainance, and documentation, I used Agile as my torch and Git as my release controller.

I developed this idea into a service that generated revenue with a strong client portfolio.

### **UX RESEARCHER**

07/2012 - 06/2013

### University of New South Wales

Created a mobile app to improve way finding for the visually impaired.

I relied on my own research methods to find out what users really want. I used video recordings and user interviews to map their mental models and designed suitable interactions. I adopted usability best practices, used success and error rates, time-based efficiency and task satisfaction metrics to make design decisions. Witnessing challenges faced by users, I published my research on the subject and continued to advocate awareness for accessibility.

yamhochi.github.io/portfolio

(experience continued)

# WEB DEVELOPER / COORDINATOR

10/2010 - 12/2011

### Huang Yao Art Foundation, Singapore

I coordinated the art foundation's web and digital infrastructure from the ground up.

Facilitating communication between stakeholders and contractors, I developed mockups, participated in storyboarding and wrote briefs to ensure visions are aligned prior production. Ensuring online prevalence, I developed a repository of reusable UI code for EDMs and microsites to support marketing efforts. I helped the foundation successfully launch its first online campaign promoting Huang Yao and his artworks.

# INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER / ILLUSTRATOR

02/2010 - 10/2010

### The Learning Grid, E-learning startup, Singapore

Joined an education startup in Singapore developing an e-learning platform for primary schools.

Worked closely with stakeholders, the founder, teachers and the students to structure content and activities for learning. Facilitated workshops and classes to gather requirements for the platform. Leveraging understanding of the students, I developed storyboards, visual content, and instructions for a series of games, videos and websites that fuelled the business. The platform gained over 5,000 within a short period of time and maintained 10% growth per month.

### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

07/2007 - 11/2007

### Brainhook Advertising, Singapore

Mentored by an international acclaimed art director at a local marketing agency. Designed various marketing collaterals for clients such as MasterCard, Ezra Marine Services, and Fullerton Hotel Singapore. Built up extensive knowledge on design fundamentals such as grid based layout, typography and print production.

## Qualifications

Master of Science and Technology (Spatial Information) University of New South Wales 2012

Bachelor of Arts (Visual Media) Griffith University, 2004 - 2009